alotresults.com 2016-06-16

# Privacy

Thank you for visiting Alot. Alot is committed to protecting consumer privacy online. We believe that greater protection of personal privacy on the Web will not only protect consumers, but also increase consumer confidence and ultimately their participation in online activities. The purpose of our policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you when you visit our site, how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of the information. Our site may contain links to other Web sites, including Web sites directed to children. We have no control over the privacy practices or the content of any of our business partners, advertisers, sponsors or other sites to which we provide links from our sites. You should check the applicable privacy policy of the Web site sponsor when linking to other Web sites. Alot strives to offer its visitors the many advantages of Internet technology and to provide an interactive and personalized experience. 

### How We Gather Information and Technologies We Use

At Alot you can visit many pages on our site without physically taking any steps to provide information. Like most Web sites, we do collect information automatically and through the use of electronic tools that may be transparent to our visitors. This section provides information about the information we collect and how the technologies we utilize work.

**__Information we gather using technology__** _ ** _._**_

  * **Cookies.  **We use "cookies." The cookies we place on your computer are very small text files that uniquely identify your browser and may be sent to your computer or mobile device. They are stored on your hard drive and communicate with our servers only when you are visiting our websites. We use cookies to improve the quality of Alot.  They allow us to monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and number of pages viewed. They also allow us to optimize Alot to make sure that we are delivering the best possible experience to our users.  Your web browser is likely already set to accept cookies, yet you may choose to block cookies in your web browser’s settings. Note that blocking cookies may result in some features not being able to function properly.  To learn more about controlling browser cookies visit: <http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1>.

Additionally, we allow third parties that display advertisements, search listings, and other content on portions of Alot to set and access their cookies on your computer or device and any cookies are subject to the applicable third parties privacy policies and not ours. These companies’ may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to Alot and other unaffiliated Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. We also partner with a limited number of interest-based advertising companies to serve ads and/or collect certain information when you visit our websites. Interest-based advertising companies may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information during your visit to our websites in order to help show advertisements on other websites likely to be more interesting to you. To learn more about this 'interest-based advertising' practice or to opt-out of this use of your anonymous information, you can go to the National Advertising Initiative's website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

  * **Device Information.  **We collect information regarding the Internet browser, computer, tablet, mobile phone, smartphone or other device utilized to access Alot to ensure that Alot is optimized for those devices.
  * **Internet Protocol Addresses.  **Internet browsers automatically transmit information such as the URL of the website you just came from and the Internet Protocol (IP) address and the browser version of your computer. This information is utilized to optimize Alot.
  * **Location Information.  **On some of our mobile applications we may (or may enable a third party to) request your geolocation information.  If allowed, we (or the third party) may use this information to supply you with location specific advertisements, offers and functionality.  Additionally, we may (or may enable a third party to) capture geolocation information (such as IP address data) when you access Alot, and may use that geo-location information to targets ads, offers and functionality.
  * **Analytics.  **We use third party information, reports and analysis about the usage and browsing patterns of users of Alot.  We allow the third party analytics companies to include web beacons and cookies on Alot. The collected information includes search terms, search parameters, click-throughs by users, and other similar information. We utilize this information to improve Alot and make sure we are delivering relevant content to our users. The Analytics we use do not identify individual users of Alot.
  * **Log Files.  **We may also automatically log certain anonymous information about visitors to Alot, including, but not limited to, where the user came from to visit our site, IP address, search terms utilized, browser type and a reading history of the pages viewed.
  * **Web Beacons.  **We (or our third party partners) may use web beacons.  Web beacons communicate information from your Internet browser to a web server. We (or our third party partners) use web beacons for a variety of purposes, including to analyze the use of Alot and in conjunction with cookies to provide content and ads that are more relevant to you.
  * **Other.  **As new technologies develop we may implement and/or test them on Alot.  We only utilize technologies as permitted by law.?

**__Information we gather because you gave it to us.__**

**In order for us to provide some of our services we collect information, including personally identifiable information, when you:**

  * **Register _.   If you register for our forums or other services we ask you to provide information which may include items such as name, address, birthdate, gender, and password._**
  * **_Sign up for Newsletters_** **.   We offer newsletters to our users and from time to time we allow third party partners to include advertising materials in the newsletters.  Additionally, we may send dedicated newsletters on behalf of our third party partners.  All of our newsletters contain a readily identifiable and simple means to opt out of receiving them in the future.**
  * **Post in Comments, Discussion Forums, Reviews and Similar Places.   Our services include public facing comments, discussion forums, reviews and other similar places where you can submit items to be posted which will be visible to the public at large.  All information posted in such manner may be used by us for commercial uses in any format.  All information submitted is not confidential or private and it may be collected and utilized by unaffiliated third parties.  You are solely responsible for the information you choose to disclose in your public activities.**

**Participate in Giveaways, Sweepstakes and Other Promotions.   We sponsor giveaways, sweepstakes and other promotions.  If you chose to participate in our giveaways, sweepstakes or promotions, your personally identifiable information may be collected, including your name and e-mail address.**

**What we do with the information we collect**

We will use your information only as permitted by law.  We use the information we collect to: optimize Alot, including ensuring that the site is accessible to your device; ensure the site is available in the appropriate language; customize the advertising and content available to you; improve our product offerings and services; optimize our marketing campaigns; conduct research; supply our third party partners with aggregate and/or anonymous information to help them enhance their own products, data, or analytics; and provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients.  We also utilize the information we collect to deliver the services you request, such as delivering newsletters, enabling participation in forums, comments, discussions, sweepstakes, and similar matters.

As we continue to develop our business, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. We may also disclose your information in response to a court order, at other times when we believe we are reasonably required to do so by law, in connection with the collection of amounts you may owe to us, and/or whenever we deem it appropriate or necessary to give such information to law enforcement authorities. Please note we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

### Affiliated sites, linked sites and advertisements

Alot expects its partners, advertisers and third-party affiliates to respect the privacy of our users. However, third parties, including our partners, advertisers, affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. For example, during your visit to our site you may link to, or view as part of a frame on Alot page, certain content that is actually created or hosted by a third party. Also, through Alot you may be introduced to, or be able to access, information, Web sites, advertisements, features, contests or sweepstakes offered by other parties. Alot is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

While on our site, our advertisers, promotional partners or other third parties may use cookies or other technology to attempt to identify some of your preferences or retrieve information about you. For example, some of our advertising is served by third parties and may include cookies that enable the advertiser to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before. Through features available on our site, third parties may use cookies or other technology to gather information. Alot does not control the use of this technology or the resulting information and is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use non-personal information (i.e., information that does not include your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in an effort to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. To learn more about third-party advertising or to opt-out of such advertising, you can visit both the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/).

In addition to the above, we have implemented at Alot certain "Google Analytics" features that support display advertising, including re-targeting. Visitors to Alot may opt out of Google Analytics, customize the Google Display Network ads by using the [Google Ad Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/) and learn more about how Google serves ads by viewing its [Customer Ads Help Center](https://support.google.com/ads/?hl=en). If you do not wish to participate in Google Analytics, you may also download the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

### Communication with Contributors

Alot Contributors provide content to Alot.  Contributors are independent contractors and not employees of Alot.  If you contact a Contributor via e-mail or otherwise then that communication is independent of Alot and is not governed by this Privacy Policy. Alot is not responsible for the actions of our Contributors or how they may use information you have provided to them. Any communications with a Contributor are not confidential or subject to any other privilege.

### Our Parent Company

Alot is a wholly-owned subsidiary of Inuvo, Inc. We share information we collect with Inuvo, Inc. to better understand our users and to improve the content delivered across the Inuvo, Inc. network.

### Minors

Alot does not knowingly solicit or collect information from visitors under thirteen (13) years of age. Alot encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate and monitor the interactive activities of their children.

If you are between the ages of 13 and 18, please be sure to read this Privacy Policy with your parent and get his or her permission before you participate in our service.

### Compliance with legal process

We may disclose information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our websites; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public.

### Changes in Privacy Policy

Alot reserves the right to change or update this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a notice at the Site explaining that we are changing our Privacy Policy.

### Users from outside the United States

**Information from Users Outside of the United States**

Visitors to Alot from outside the United States will have their data transferred to and stored in our servers in the U.S. By using Alot, international users are consenting to our use and collection of their data as described herein.

### Contacting the site

We listen to or read, as applicable, every message sent to us and endeavor to reply promptly to each one. This information is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices of Alot, please feel free to contact us at [info@alot.com](mailto:info@alot.com).

Last updated: May 12, 2016
